{"Topic": "Gases", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Carbon dioxide is called a greenhouse gas because", "op1": "Its concentration remains always higher than other gases", "op2": "It is used in photosynthesis", "op3": "It absorbs infrared  radiation", "op4": "It emits visible radiation", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the major role of a greenhouse gas that contributes to temperature rise of the earth\u2019s surface?", "op1": "Transparent to both incoming sunlight and outgoing infrared radiation", "op2": "Stops both incoming sunlight and outgoing infrared radiation", "op3": "Lets outgoing infrared radiation pass through but stops incoming sunlight", "op4": "Lets incoming sunlight pass through but stops outgoing infrared radiation", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Consider the following statements:", "op1": "1 and 2", "op2": "1 and 3", "op3": "2 and 3", "op4": "3 and 4", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "ch of the statements given above are correct?", "op1": "Acetylene", "op2": "Ethane", "op3": "Methane", "op4": "Carbon dioxide", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which among the following nontoxic gases helps in formation of enzymes which ripen fruit?", "op1": "Ethanol", "op2": "Thioethanol", "op3": "Methane", "op4": "Chloroform", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one among the following is strong smelling agent added to LPG cylinder to help in the detection of gas leakage?", "op1": "1 only", "op2": "2 only", "op3": "Both 1 and 2", "op4": "Neither 1 nor 2", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following statements regarding ozone layer within the atmosphere is/are correct?", "op1": "Methane", "op2": "butane", "op3": "ethane", "op4": "propane", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "ect the correct answer using the code given below:", "op1": "wind", "op2": "Air Current", "op3": "Air turbulence", "op4": "Air mobility", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The major component in LPG is", "op1": "Electrolysis of water", "op2": "Fractional distillation of liquid air", "op3": "Decomposition of potassium permanganate", "op4": "Decomposition of manganese dioxide", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The vertical movement of air is termed as", "op1": "allotropes", "op2": "isomers", "op3": "isotopes", "op4": "isobars", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not a method of preparing oxygen?", "op1": "Troposphere", "op2": "Ionosphere", "op3": "Stratosphere", "op4": "Exosphere", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Oxygen and ozone are", "op1": "Troposphere", "op2": "Stratosphere", "op3": "Mesosphere", "op4": "Thermosphere", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Ozone layer is present in", "op1": "Carbon dioxide", "op2": "Methane", "op3": "Hydrogen", "op4": "Nitrogen Dioxide", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which is the lowest layer of the atmosphere ?", "op1": "Day time", "op2": "Night time", "op3": "Both", "op4": "Seasonal", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is a major constituent of Biogas?", "op1": "Calcium Tetra Flouride", "op2": "Diflouro Dichloro Methane", "op3": "Flourspar and Felspar", "op4": "Hydrofluosilicic Acid", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Sea breeze is formed during", "op1": "Sodium", "op2": "Neon", "op3": "Hydrogen", "op4": "Nitrogen", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The Refrigerant 'FREON' is", "op1": "Gravity", "op2": "Winds", "op3": "Clouds", "op4": "Rotation of the earth", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Now a days, Yellow lamps are frequently used as street lights. Which among the following gases, is used in these lamps?", "op1": "Helium", "op2": "Argon", "op3": "Krypton", "op4": "Radon", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The atmospheric air is held to the earth by", "op1": "4 - 6", "op2": "2 - 4", "op3": "8 - 10", "op4": "12 - 16", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The Noble Gas used for the treatment of cancer is ___?", "op1": "it is closest to the Sun", "op2": "there are charged particles in it", "op3": "it is heated by the Earth\u2019s surface", "op4": "heat is generated in it"}, {"Question": "The optimum dissolved oxygen level (in mg/litre) required for survival of aquatic organisms is"}, {"Question": "The gas which turns limewater milky is", "op1": "carbon dioxide", "op2": "carbon monoxide", "op3": "ammonia", "op4": "nitrogen dioxide", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the lightest gas?", "op1": "hydrogen", "op2": "helium", "op3": "xenon", "op4": "radon", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Hydrogen is not found in atmosphere because", "op1": "It is highly inflammable", "op2": "It is the lightest gas", "op3": "It is absorbed by plants", "op4": "It immediately combines with oxygen to form water", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The gas used for filling weather balloons is", "op1": "Helium", "op2": "Hydrogen", "op3": "Air", "op4": "Nitrogen", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What is the chemical name of Laughing Gas?", "op1": "Silver nitrate", "op2": "Sodium carbonate", "op3": "Calcium sulphate", "op4": "Nitrous oxide", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The coloured discharge tubes for advertisement mainly contain", "op1": "Xenon", "op2": "Argon", "op3": "Helium", "op4": "Neon", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following noble gases is not found in the atmosphere (negligible quantity)?", "op1": "Argon", "op2": "Krypton", "op3": "Radon", "op4": "Xenon", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "For respiration in deep sea, divers use mixture of", "op1": "Oxygen and helium", "op2": "Oxygen and hydrogen", "op3": "Oxygen and carbon dioxide", "op4": "Oxygen and nitrogen", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Gases used to prepare Ammonia gas are", "op1": "Nitrogen and Oxygen", "op2": "Nitrogen and Oxide", "op3": "Nitrogen and Hydrogen", "op4": "Nitrogen and Carbon", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following gases is opaque to outgoing terrestial radiation but transparent to incoming solar radiation?", "op1": "Oxygen", "op2": "Carbondioxide", "op3": "Nitrogen", "op4": "Helium", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "In oxygen, things :", "op1": "burn dimly", "op2": "burn brightly", "op3": "do not burn at all", "op4": "burn rapidly and are immediately reduced to ashes", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG) consists of mainly :", "op1": "methane, ethane and hexane", "op2": "ethane, butane and propane", "op3": "ethane, hexane and nonane", "op4": "nonane, ethane and hexane", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The gas produced by pouring water on calcium carbide is :", "op1": "Pentane", "op2": "Methane", "op3": "Ethane", "op4": "Acetylene", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following gases is considered a better substitute to air in car tyres?", "op1": "Hydrogen", "op2": "Nitrogen", "op3": "Helium", "op4": "Oxygen", "Answer": 1}]}